<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>design on Dan Frakes</title>
    <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/tags/design/</link>
    <description>Recent content in design on Dan Frakes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://dpfrakes.github.io/tags/design/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Annoying by Design</title>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/annoying-by-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/annoying-by-design/</guid>
      <description>It&amp;rsquo;s no secret that the most successful apps, games, and social media platforms dedicate considerable effort into making their product addictive. If they don&amp;rsquo;t, consumers would be less likely to use their product, making it less valuable to advertisers.
60 Minutes presented a segment back in 2018 titled &amp;ldquo;Brain Hacking&amp;rdquo; (link) that explained how intentional these addictive features are.
The NIH published an article in 2019, listing several common &amp;ldquo;psychological mechanisms&amp;rdquo; that are built into social media and other smartphone apps (link).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bi-Directional Data Architecture</title>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/bidirectional-data-architecture/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/bidirectional-data-architecture/</guid>
      <description>I constantly think of software, data, and other technical components of my job in terms of analogies. It&amp;rsquo;s a great teaching mechanism, particularly for visual learners such as myself.
Analogies have greatly impacted terminology in software for a long time. Data pipelines are so named as information &amp;ldquo;flows&amp;rdquo; from a source to a destination. Neural networks, and their building blocks called perceptrons, are named after neurological terminology since the design of these structures was inspired by the brain.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
