<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>work on Dan Frakes</title>
    <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/tags/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in work on Dan Frakes</description>
    <image>
      <url>https://dpfrakes.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</url>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/%3Clink%20or%20path%20of%20image%20for%20opengraph,%20twitter-cards%3E</link>
    </image>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://dpfrakes.github.io/tags/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>JS Bookmarklets</title>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/web-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/web-snippets/</guid>
      <description>I have way too many browser bookmarks, but there is one folder of bookmarks I use regularly: bookmarklets.
Just as you can save an HTML webpage as a bookmark, you can also save Javascript script as a bookmarklet, basically turning your bookmarks bar into a control panel.
javascript:(function(){alert(&amp;#39;hello!&amp;#39;)})() caption: a very basic javascript snippet
Caution: make sure you know exactly what the bookmarklet is going to do before you run it or add it to your bookmarks bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sabbatical</title>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/sabbatical/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/sabbatical/</guid>
      <description>Sabbatical Plan I&amp;rsquo;m taking a break from full-time work for at least a few weeks, probably a few months.
While we&amp;rsquo;re far from early retirement, Christina and I have saved enough money to support this temporary venture into voluntary unemployment. And based on the current demand for experienced professionals in both our respective fields, we are confident that both of us will find suitable and profitable work when we choose to pursue it, barring an economic paradigm shift large enough to displace other skilled workers who hadn&amp;rsquo;t taken a sabbatical.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/toolkit/</guid>
      <description>Toolkit or bookshelf are both options.
 Cloud Providers  Amazon Web Services Google Cloud Platform Microsoft Azure   DevOps  Infrastructure  Terraform Vagrant   Tooling  Docker Nomad Consul Ansible Packer   CI/CD  Jenkins CircleCI Google Cloud Build Travis CI Concourse Azure Pipelines GitHub Actions GitLab CI Buildkite Harness     Application  Python   Data Science  Data Management  OpenRefine Xplenty Informatica Cloud Data Integration SAS Data Quality   Data Analysis  Jupyter Notebook Jupyter Lab R Studio     Network  Istio Traefik Pilot Traefik Enterprise Traefik Proxy Traefik Mesh HAProxy Kong Nginx Envoy Ambassador Caddy AWS ELB    By Organization Amazon (AWS)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workforce Problems</title>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/workforce-problems/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/workforce-problems/</guid>
      <description>https://www.bloomberg.com/news/articles/2021-06-11/fewer-young-men-are-in-the-labor-force-more-are-living-at-home
Average tenure at companies is decreasing, especially in tech
Huge demand for tech talent
Why the disconnect?
Theory: tech expectations are too high
Look at job listings. Jobs require half a decade of experience in Docker, Linux, JS, React, Node, everything
What if we applied Unix philosophy to our job market?
Do one thing and do it well
Stop hiring full-stack, do-everything, superstar rockstar ninjas
Hire experts at one thing</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
