<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>education on Dan Frakes</title>
    <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/tags/education/</link>
    <description>Recent content in education on Dan Frakes</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><atom:link href="https://dpfrakes.github.io/tags/education/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Analogies and Illustrations of a Computer</title>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/tech-stack-visualization/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/tech-stack-visualization/</guid>
      <description>Basics  Directories, files, and executables Hard drives HTTP  Intermediate  VPN (tunnel) $PATH (&amp;ldquo;cutting in line&amp;rdquo; analogy)  Advanced  Database indexing (creating a table of contents) Virtual environments, Docker Cache, RAM, storage SSD vs HDD ML algorithms  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>JS Bookmarklets</title>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/web-snippets/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/web-snippets/</guid>
      <description>I have way too many browser bookmarks, but there is one folder of bookmarks I use regularly: bookmarklets.
Just as you can save an HTML webpage as a bookmark, you can also save Javascript script as a bookmarklet, basically turning your bookmarks bar into a control panel.
javascript:(function(){alert(&amp;#39;hello!&amp;#39;)})() caption: a very basic javascript snippet
Caution: make sure you know exactly what the bookmarklet is going to do before you run it or add it to your bookmarks bar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Machine Learning Recipe</title>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/ml-recipe/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/ml-recipe/</guid>
      <description>X = ingredients
Theta = measurements/amounts
Y = taste</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Toolkit</title>
      <link>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/toolkit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://dpfrakes.github.io/posts/toolkit/</guid>
      <description>Toolkit or bookshelf are both options.
 Cloud Providers  Amazon Web Services Google Cloud Platform Microsoft Azure   DevOps  Infrastructure  Terraform Vagrant   Tooling  Docker Nomad Consul Ansible Packer   CI/CD  Jenkins CircleCI Google Cloud Build Travis CI Concourse Azure Pipelines GitHub Actions GitLab CI Buildkite Harness     Application  Python   Data Science  Data Management  OpenRefine Xplenty Informatica Cloud Data Integration SAS Data Quality   Data Analysis  Jupyter Notebook Jupyter Lab R Studio     Network  Istio Traefik Pilot Traefik Enterprise Traefik Proxy Traefik Mesh HAProxy Kong Nginx Envoy Ambassador Caddy AWS ELB    By Organization Amazon (AWS)</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
